# Artur Vanivskyi - Software Engineer

New York City, NY | 646-830-9748 | vanivskyi.artur@gmail.com | Linkedin | GitHub | Portfolio

#### **SUMMARY**

Full-Stack software engineer proficient in using JavaScript for front-end and back-end programming, React, HTML, CSS, API implementing, Node.JS, Express, PostgreSQL, GoLang. Strong background in developing logical and methodical solutions to challenging problems. Experienced in working on a team and independent projects to develop adaptable and professional software on time and on budget. A exceptional eye for detail and design, allowing development of visually pleasing and user-friendly websites. Devoted to perpetual learning and being open to change, consistently striving to adapt.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

*Frontend:* HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, jQuery, TypeScript. *Backend:* Node.is, Express, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL, GoLang.

Tools: Mocha, Chai, Knex, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Node Package Manager, Visual Studio Code, Bootstrap.

Additional Skills: Ukrainian:fluent, Russian:fluent, Polish:Intermediate, Microsoft Office: Word, Excel, excellent

communication and interpersonal skills.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

X-line Glass&Mirror Remote

## Freelance Frontend Developer |

11/2022 - 02/2023

- Designed and developed a responsive, single-page website for X-line Glass&Mirror company using JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, and Swiper.is.
- Ensured the website was optimized for both desktop and mobile devices using responsive design techniques.
- Utilized Swiper.js to create a dynamic and interactive user experience.
- Created schema for users and products using Python.

Thinkful Remote

# **Full-Stack Engineering Student**

06/2022 - 11/2022

- Learned industry best practices and software development standards with a focus on JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React Native, Node.js, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs, algorithms, and data structures.
- Developed and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks, spending several hours per week collaborating with senior web developers in a mentor-student relationship.
- Experienced in building and connecting projects with 3rd party API / systems.
- Produced professional projects from concept to completion including:

# o E-commerce: Crown Shop | Project Link

- Developed an e-commerce platform with user-friendly interface to provide customers with easy access to products, with focus on front-end development.
- Implemented sign-in and google sign-in functionality.
- Integrated a payment component using Stripe to enable customers to securely make transactions.
- Used serverless functions to connect front-end and database: Firebase.
- Utilized Redux Saga to maintain clean state management in an e-commerce platform.
- Technology: JavaScript, React, Redux, CSS and FireBase, Stripe. Version control with Git.

#### Restaurant Reservation System | Project Link

- Full stack reservation and table management system.
- Implemented react router and express to build a RESTful API in order to make HTTP requests for all
  of the reservation data stored on the connected PostgreSQL database.
- Used testing frameworks and automated tests.
- Created CRUD functions and Knex queries to handle data going to and coming from the database.
- Used Git to track changes while keeping sensitive information from being pushed to repositories.
- Technology: React, CSS, Node.js, Express, Knex and PostgreSQL.

## BusinessCard Holder "Vancard" | Project Link

- Full stack business card holder system.
- Originated and applied CRUD functions and queries to manage sending and retrieving data in
- Used Git to track changes while keeping sensitive information from being pushed to repositories.
- Programmed react router and express to build REST APIs.
- Technology: Node.js, Express, and Knex. Version control with Git, JavaScript, CSS flexbox, React.

Masal / Masal Plus

Brooklyn, NY 04/2018 - 08/2022

- Manager
  - Formulated pricing policies by reviewing merchandising activities, and determined needed sales promotions. Completed store operational requirements by scheduling and assigning employees, and followed up on results.
  - Maintained store staff by recruiting, selecting, orienting, and training 40-50 employees.
  - Prepared an annual budget and achieved financial objectives by saving an average of \$2500 per month.
  - Proven experience in effectively interfacing with customers to identify their needs and gather feedback on services.

GasInfoService startup

Ukraine/USA

## Project Manager of Geology and Geophysics department

05/2016 - 08/2017

- Developed a database of various businesses which use and convey equipment used in the Geology and Geophysics surveys and closed 24 deals for the company, bringing in \$50K.
- Presented at conferences, pitching the company and its services, to gain new clients and partners.
- Proficient in organizing and coordinating resources to execute projects effectively.
- Built the structure for the web page in the Geology and Geophysics section, reviewing the JavaScript code.
- Worked on with a team of engineers to implement new features and bug fixes.
- Introduced web-design for Geology and Geophysics section using Figma, Tailwind.
- Used Excel for data entry and data analysis.

### **EDUCATION**

JPMorgan Software Engineering Virtual Experience Program on Forage	Online
Certificate	05/2023
Thinkful	Online
Certificate, Software Engineering	11/2022
AGH University of Science and Technology	Cracow, Poland
MS, Applied Geophysics	02/2017
Ivano-Frankivsk National Technical University of Oil and Gas	Ivano-Frankivsk, Ukraine
MS, Geophysics	02/2017
Ivano-Frankivsk National Technical University of Oil and Gas	Ivano-Frankivsk, Ukraine
B.S, Geology	06/2015